# Patricia E. Miguel

email@patriciaemiguel.com | (+54) 9 236 4301080 | Argentina | linkedin.com/in/patriciaemiguel

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

**Software Engineer (back-end focused)** with a diverse background in **quality assurance** (automation and manual testing), university-level **teaching**, and educational content creation. Experienced in **C#** and **Python**, with a passion for teaching, public speaking, and creating engaging technical content. Strong **communication skills** (fluent in English and Spanish), leadership experience (from community projects), and a proven ability to explain complex technical concepts to diverse audiences.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

• **Ssr. Fullstack Software Developer** (2024 – present) at Tu tutú (www.tututu.app/sobre-tu-tutu) Project: Middle-Sea (insurance broker).

Tools used: .Net framework 4.7.2, C#, NUnit, SQL Server, NHibernate, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap. Responsibilities: Backend-focused tasks. Develop features and introduce required changes in the various platforms the broker uses, both in their intranet and client-facing. Integrate third-party APIs from insurance companies. Unit testing. Manage test environment deployment. Agile methodology (scrum / kanban). Web applications. 100% Remote.

• **Backend Software Engineer** (2021 – 2023) at Intive (www.intive.com)

Project: "Shippo" (a Shippo multi-carrier shipping platform for e-commerce).

Tools used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS, Postman, Git, Bitbucket, CircleCI, Linux. Responsibilities: Back-end developer. Integrate courier APIs (both REST and SOAP) into the Shippo product. Bug-fixing. Unit and integration tests.

Agile methodology (scrum). Web application. 100% Remote.

• **Senior QA Analyst** (2018 – 2021) at Intive (www.intive.com)

Project: "Digital Workspace" (a Sabre Corporation GDS).

Tools used: Jira, TestCafe (Javascript automation framework), Git, Rally, HP ALM.

Responsibilities: Create and automate test cases, refine user stories, advise on clarification of business logic details for implementation, execution of tests on web, desktop and mobile applications, create and manage defect reports, coaching peers.

Automated and manual testing. Agile methodology (scrum, kanban). Desktop/web/mobile environments. 100% Remote.

• **Quality Engineer** (2011 – 2018) at Clarolab (www.clarolab.com)

Projects: "Jive" (a Jive Software social networking platform for business applications), Sharepoint-based intranet (a Threewill project for AT&T USA), "Jama Contour" (a Jama Software platform for development & engineering process).

Tools used: Selenium webdriver, Robot Framework (on Java), Python, Git, Stash, Jenkins, Linux, Jira, TestRail, Web Accessibility Evaluation Tool, CodeSniffer, Firebug, JAWS and NVDA screenreaders. Responsibilities: Functional testing, bug triage, test case creation and manual execution, accessibility testing, UX analysis, test automation and maintenance, database interaction, test environment maintenance. Live testing of the Image Gallery app during Jive World 2012.

Agile methodology (scrum). Web application testing. Hybrid (Junín, Buenos Aires).

• **Freelance tester** (2013 – 2015) at Utest (www.utest.com), remote crowdsourcing (tester ID 95308, username "patr1c1a").

Responsibilities: Functional and internationalization testing. Find and report issues. Execute test cases.

Projects include: Netflix, YouTube, MalwareBytes, King.com, Yandex, Crackle, CBS Interactive, Time Warner Residential, Autodesk, Concur, 123D Design Online, Snapfish UK, 3-Wheel, WatchDox, Acquia, among others.

Tools used: Logcat for Android, multiple OS (Win 7, Win 8.1, Ubuntu, Android), multiple desktop and mobile browsers (IE 6-9, Safari, Chrome, Firefox, Opera), Drupal, Bug Reporter (Android), SpeedTest.net (Android), screenshot/video tools.

Highest rating achieved: "gold rated" Software QA in both functional and internationalization areas. Web, desktop and mobile testing. 100% Remote.

• **Programming Teacher** (2010 – 2019) at UNNOBA university (www.unnoba.edu.ar)

Positions: Teaching Assistant, pro bono, from 2010 to 2014. Teacher (lab instructor) from 2014 to 2019.

Responsibilities: Teach classes. Deliver tailored teaching activities to students. Create teaching resources and exams. Grading exams and deliverables. Facilitate student learning and help them solve programming problems and logical reasoning exercises. On site.

Courses: "Introduction to Imperative Programming", "Imperative Programming", Freshmen introductory course.

Languages taught: Python, C++, Pascal.

Grants awarded: research at Rey Juan Carlos University (Madrid, Spain, March 2017).

On site (Junín, Buenos Aires).

## **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Information Systems (Licenciatura en Sistemas) UNNOBA, Argentina (2022). 5-year program, equivalent to a Bachelor's degree in Information Systems.
- Associate Degree in Systems Analysis (Analista de Sistemas) UNNOBA, Argentina (2014). 3-year Intermediate Degree.
- **Diploma in Computer Programming (Programador Universitario)** *UNNOBA, Argentina* (2014). 2-year Technical Program.
- Bachelor of Laws (Abogacía) and Specialization in Notarial Practice (Escribanía) UNLP, Argentina (2008). 5-year program and 1-year postgraduate program.

### **PUBLIC TALKS**

Public talks and workshops where I participated as a speaker or instructor.

• Instructor during the 2021 summer workshop at "Club de Chicas Programadoras" (www.chicasprogramadoras.club)

An introduction to programming aimed at girls aged 13-17, with the intention of inspiring young women to get involved in technology. Tools and technologies used: Scratch, HTML/CSS, MIT App Inventor.

6 online sessions.

• "Using Postman to test an API" at online event: "Jump! Conference" (www.vamosalajump.com)
As a current software developer and a former senior QA engineer, I delivered this talk, aimed at professionals starting their careers.

Youtube link: https://youtu.be/MLN2ub61bnk?t=7234

### **LANGUAGES**

- English (Fluent)
- Spanish (Native)

#### **INTERESTS**

Creating educational content, singing (choir member), tango dancing, history enthusiast, former Rotary Club (Interact, Rotaract) member.

#### SOCIAL MEDIA AND ONLINE PRESENCE

My channel, blog and social media where I post educational content for programming beginners. Contents are only in Spanish so far.

- **Blog:** www.patriciaemiguel.com
- Youtube channel: www.youtube.com/c/ProgramacionDesdeCero
- Instagram: www.instagram.com/programaciondesdecero
- **Facebook:** www.facebook.com/ProgramacionDesdeCer0
- X (Twitter): www.x.com/Programacion\_0